OUR STICKY LOVE
It might have been a memory, not a dream.
If Jang Tae-ha's really a gangster,
this might also
have something to do with him.
Isn't it enough you've ruined your life
with violence already?
Now you want to drag Pil-seung
into that fiery hell with you?
Not my boy.
I won't let you!
Mrs. Pang!
No matter how angry you are,
there are things you just don't say.
Everything else aside,
how can you do this when you know
why Tae-ha went down that path?
I also won't stand by
and watch my boy get hurt.
I'm sorry we didn't tell you sooner
about Pil-seung,
but if you want to blame or sue anyone,
blame me, the head coach.
Don't take it out on Tae-ha!
You're right.
I went too far.
It's not that I don't know
what you've been through.
I just lost my temper
out of concern for my boy.
And I know that not all boxers
become gangsters,
but it's easier to fall in with those guys
than other jobs.
I was scared that those punks
might start eyeing my kid.
What kind of mother would want that?
Please try to understand me, Tae-ha.
Let's go. Come on.
Wait, Mom.
Oh, shut it.
Mom, please.
Ms. Go.
Whoa! Hey, what?
You scared me.
Didn't you see me?
Are you okay?
Are you…
okay?
You know I can take a hit.
I'm just worried about Pil-seung.
What, you think he goes down easy?
He's probably butting heads with his mom,
going a few rounds.
Fancy a drink?
I should go home.
All right.
It's a good thing you have someone at home
on a day like this.
The warmth of someone being home.
It makes a difference.
I'll get going.
This morning, the ceremony
for the Irang-dong development project
was attended by Gangju City officials
and Mirae Eden Company representatives.
This project is a joint effort between
Gangju City and Mirae Eden Company,
and the plan is to complete
the development in three phases by 2029.
Though the blueprint for this project
was presented in 2020,
it was effectively halted
due to the real estate market downturn.
But earlier this year,
the development area was…
Go Eun-sae.
Drink this. It'll help you calm down.
Do you still not believe Tae-ha?
I believed him
a little bit.
In the midst of this absurd situation,
there were moments
when he seemed sincere.
Sorry I don't express myself well.
You're the only woman I've ever liked,
so I don't really know how.
He wasn't exactly my ideal type,
but he didn't seem like
a bad person either.
I never knew she was so pretty.
But it turns out he's a gangster.
And everything he said to me was a lie.
Apparently, my name isn't even Go Eun-sae.
It's Go Ji-won.
Sorry?
I don't know where to start
questioning things again,
or why Jang Tae-ha lied to me
about all of this,
and what I'm supposed to do now.
I don't know anything anymore.
I'm scared.
Go Eun-sae!
Eun-sae…
Hello?
It's me, Min Su-ji.
Right. I can't really talk right now…
Are you looking for Ms. Go?
Is she here?
Yes.
I heard her telling Gi-jun
that she found out you're a gangster.
And that her name is Go Ji-won,
not Go Eun-sae.
She said she saw
her friend's social media.
What's going on?
Is she really your girlfriend?
Now, then…
-What should we do?
-Sorry?
I understand your situation,
but that doesn't mean…
I can't exactly let you crash at my place.
And I can't lend you money for a place
to stay, since you can't pay me back.
Doctor.
Yes?
You don't have many
friends, do you?
No, I guess I don't.
I was just joking to cheer you up.
Come on.
You were being serious.
Well, I'm sorry.
Jang Tae-ha.
I'll explain everything, so let's go home.
How can I trust a thug and go with him?
You should trust what you've experienced.
Has he ever been a threat to you?
Has he ever threatened you,
used violence, or extorted you?
If not, then Tae-ha isn't a thug to you.
He's just
an ordinary man, isn't he?
Let's talk outside.
-Go Eun-sae.
-But I'm not Go Eun-sae.
I'm Go Ji-won, aren't I?
Go Ji-won is your legal name.
Eun-sae is the name your mother gave you.
Are you getting caught up
in your own lies? My mother?
You said I was an orphan.
Your mother left you at an orphanage
right after you were born.
The orphanage head only realized
after registering your birth
under the name Go Ji-won
that your name was Go Eun-sae
in your mother's maternity notebook.
You liked the name Go Eun-sae better.
You said she wouldn't have given
such a pretty name
to a baby she didn't love.
You didn't even resent her
for abandoning you.
And the designer goods?
I saw pictures of me and my friend.
I was dressed from head to toe
in designer items.
Then why don't I have anything like that
in my closet or shoe rack?
You got rid of them when we moved.
-Why?
-I never asked why.
I…
I'm sorry that I was…
a gangster.
I was too ashamed to tell you.
If I'd known you were a thug,
I wouldn't have believed a word you said.
If I know anything,
it's that I'd never,
not in this life or any other,
fall for some lowlife gangster.
I don't do that anymore.
I won't ever use my fists
outside the ring anymore.
I promise.
No, forget it.
Just why are you putting on this act
to keep me here?
What in the world do you want from me?
Nothing else.
Just don't disappear without a word.
Just stay out of danger.
Just…
Just stay safe.
Why are you overreacting?
How would you know
if he's really Ms. Go's boyfriend?
He is her boyfriend.
Is she really your girlfriend?
Is Eun-sae okay?
-What?
-Has she been crying?
Is she hurt?
Go inside.
Ms. Go is fine.
Do you remember when we went to Yeosu,
and I left the hotel after we argued?
Why are you bringing that up now?
Was it right to ghost me for hours
because you were mad?
I got lost back then.
I was just gonna cool off, then go back,
but you know I get lost easily.
I was in an unfamiliar city,
and I'd left my phone behind.
I was terrified.
When I got back to the hotel
after wandering for hours,
you asked if I was happy I'd win
by making you worry.
Perhaps the one
who was never really a boyfriend
isn't Tae-ha,
but you.
PARK HYO-JIN
HYOGENIE_1227
HI. THIS IS JI-WON.
YOU'RE MY FRIEND, HYO-JIN, RIGHT?
Please read it.
Please read it and get back to me.
Hey, hey, don't run
You'll only get hungrier
This heart-aching road of the barley hump…
Hey there, Song-wol.
These are dried persimmons.
Put them in the freezer
and eat them with your grandma.
How did you ever live through those days?
Mother's sorrow
Endless days of living on roots and bark
-Have you been well, ma'am?
-As those times fade into the wind
-I haven't been able to visit you lately.
-Mother's sorrow, buried…
Are you happy that Tae-ha moved down here?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm so sorry.
I said something
I shouldn't have to Tae-ha.
Despite knowing why he ended up like that
and everything you went through
to raise him,
I was blinded by my love for my own child.
So I drove a nail
into poor Tae-ha's heart.
Even though I have two children of my own,
and I've grown older,
I still have a long way to go…
before I can call myself a true adult.
I'll make sure to prepare
the grandest of celebrations
for your 80th birthday.
I know that couldn't possibly
make up for my mistake, but still.
Please go… a little easy on me.
You're telling me to stop whining
and shut up, right?
Please stay with us for a long time.
Until this fool, Pang Hui-ja,
finally grows up.
It's me, Hyo-jin.
I'm texting after seeing your DM.
Let's meet.
It's okay now. I'm okay.
HONG DO-YEOP
Hi, Coach.
Who's here?
Something's come up.
These are Grandma's favorite playlists.
Give them to Mrs. Pang at the party.
What?
Her only grandson is skipping her party?
She'll need these, so make sure you go.
Go there and stay put.
What's with him?
What's more important than his grandma?
Sir!
It's me, Gang-rok!
Have you been well?
Sir, they sliced my Achilles' heel.
If you leave, they usually cut off both,
but I'm such a small fry
that they let me off with one.
You were like a father to me.
Why would I stay in Eden
when my dad's not there?
How did you find me?
Ages ago, we drank together,
just the two of us.
You got drunk
and told me about your hometown.
You said you wanted to go back
to the boxing gym there when you retired.
I looked it up,
and there's only one boxing gym in Gujin.
I must ask…
Sir,
did you save Prosecutor Go?
I saw her earlier,
very much alive.
CONGRATULATIONS ON
MS. GO YEON-HONG'S 80TH BIRTHDAY
Nice!
Here.
There you go.
All right, here goes!
I was told to give this to Mrs. Pang.
They're songs Grandma likes.
I'll get going, then.
Hang on, lady.
Where are you going? Eat before you go.
It's okay.
Hold on.
Aren't you her granddaughter-in-law?
First, you show up fashionably late.
And now what?
You're gonna show your face and leave?
I'm not her granddaughter-in-law.
Sure, you haven't had a wedding yet,
but you're practically her family.
-I'll get going.
-What?
-I said eat before you go.
-I said I don't want to.
You shouldn't go on an empty stomach.
At least eat this before you go.
Oh my!
Go Ji-won!
I said I'll make you eat gochujang
if you leave food, didn't I?
Eat it!
Eat! I said eat!
Open!
Open your mouth! Wide!
Have you lost all your manners?
Hey, you can make a scene,
but there are lines you don't cross.
She did that so you wouldn't go hungry.
Yeah, but… did I ever say I was hungry?
Did I say I wanted to eat?
People in the countryside might think
that's how you show affection,
but it's only affection if it's welcome.
Forcing food on someone
who doesn't want to eat
is torture.
What? Torture?
Hey, don't you have parents?
Didn't your parents teach you
to be respectful?
No.
Apparently, I don't have any parents
and grew up in an orphanage.
-What's going on?
-What's happening?
What?
But what difference
would parents have made?
You have parents, and I don't,
yet we're being equally disrespectful.
I should seriously knock some sense
into that thick head of yours!
I could also speak rudely to you,
but I'm holding back.
You should know that, at the very least,
compared to everyone here,
I have a certain level of class and grace,
so I'm letting this slide.
So what brings someone of such class
to the countryside?
That's why I'm leaving.
Because I can't bear to stay
in this low-class village
for another day.
-Look at her.
-Ms. Go.
-Let her go.
-That brat! Good heavens.
Hui-ja, just let it go.
Just let her go.
Yeah, why wait until tomorrow?
To Seoul, please.
I thought that was just like you, sir.
The man I served all this time
has always been above taking a life.
So does Prosecutor Go live here now?
Has she given up being a prosecutor?
Is it to stay off the chairman's radar?
-Gang-rok.
-Yes, sir?
Why are you here?
I want to live here too.
I don't care what we do.
I just want to be with you.
Please take me in.
There's something you don't know.
Sorry?
Taking someone's life
is not beneath me.
When it comes to protecting my people,
nothing's beneath me.
That means that if you came here
with a hidden agenda…
I will kill you.
I don't have one.
Please believe me.
DO JEONG-HWA
Hello.
I'm sorry?
I should've done this sooner.
Now I can breathe.
Just don't disappear without a word.
Just stay out of danger.
No.
You did well.
It'll all be over tomorrow.
JANG TAE-HA
6 MISSED CALLS
You've held up well all this time.
Go Eun-sae!
Eun-sae!
GO EUN-SAE
Go Eun-sae, please.
The phone is turned off.
You will be directed to voicemail.
Please leave a message…
Where the hell did you go?
If it's Seoul…
If you went to Seoul…
No. Please, no.
We have so many eyes in Seoul.
Did you think
you'd go unseen?
Prosecutor.
Go Eun-sae!
No!
KIM GANG-ROK
Sir, I thought about it all night.
If Prosecutor Go doesn't have any ID,
whose name did she use
to get a phone number?
Why do you ask?
Today's finally the day.
Now I'll finally find out…
the truth.
Hyo-jin?
Yeah.
It's me, Park Hyo-jin.
Thanks.
So we really are friends.
I finally met my best friend.
TO HYO-JIN
FROM EUN-SAE
"Eun-sae"?
Isn't my name Go Ji-won?
That's your legal name.
Go Eun-sae is the name your mom gave you.
You liked that name better,
so I called you Eun-sae sometimes.
Go Ji-won is your legal name.
Eun-sae is the name your mother gave you.
I see.
But do you really
not remember anything?
Yeah. When I opened my eyes,
I was in the hospital.
I couldn't remember a thing.
Then this boxing coach from the country
showed up out of the blue,
saying that we'd been living together
for two years.
That I was an orphan with no family.
It was just impossible to believe.
What did I use to do?
What that man said…
is all true.
What?
You did grow up in an orphanage,
your boyfriend was a boxing coach,
and you didn't have a job as such.
Wait, but that… can't be true.
In all your Instagram photos,
I was dressed in designer clothes.
Who do you think bought that for you?
-What?
-Be good to your boyfriend.
He took care of you despite who you were.
But…
Why…
As my friend, why would you
talk about me like that?
We're friends.
Yeah.
We…
used to be.
I'll get you your drink and rice.
-Thanks.
-Can I get you anything else?
-We're good, thanks.
-Enjoy your meal.
-Hey, come here.
-What is it?
Switch shoes with me.
What?
Forget it.
Come on, I want my legs to look longer.
There's a cute customer over there.
Hurry.
-My feet are cold.
-Why are you barefoot?
-Hey, careful.
-I'm okay.
-I'm going.
-Hey.
Go Eun-sae, seriously?
We met in our early twenties
while working part-time.
We clicked and quickly became friends.
Is that right?
You're right. I am in the area, but…
Yes.
No, it's fine.
Yes, understood, sir.
I'm sorry. My boss just called me,
and I think I have to go.
But you just got here.
There's an important drinks thing.
You told me to come no matter what,
so I even closed my nail salon.
Come on, you can't compare
closing your salon to my work drinks.
How much does your salon make in a day?
Let's say it's 70,000 won per appointment.
I'll send you 700,000 won.
-What?
-I'm sorry.
See you!
But at a certain point, you changed.
What? Hyo-jin bought this?
But this costs over five million won.
She said she considered it for months
before buying it.
I guess she'll be back for a refund.
Time and time again, you hurt me.
You often made me feel
miserable and humiliated.
I really did that?
It's not that I wasn't worried
when you went missing,
but knowing that the person
who hurt me was gone
wasn't so bad.
Now that I've seen you're okay,
please don't contact me anymore.
Wait. I'm sorry.
I'm just having a hard time
believing what you're saying right now.
There isn't a single designer item
in the house I live in right now.
How do you explain that?
You're not lying to me, too, are you?
Ji-won.
Isn't it obvious why you wouldn't have
the designer items you bought?
You returned them.
Or sold them because you needed money.
That's why
you should've known
to live within your means.
Wait, I…
SORRY FOR NOT OPENING THE DOOR
WHY AM I ALWAYS SO SORRY?
At the very least,
compared to everyone here,
I have a certain level of class and grace,
so I'm letting this slide.
Class? What class?
I was the lowest of them all.
If the phone is under your name,
can't we track it?
These days, they can track your phone
with your consent if you lose it.
What do I do?
I'm the worst.
Go Eun-sae.
Why are you on the street like this?
What are you doing here?
Forget it. I don't want to talk about it.
Let's just go home.
How could I go back there?
I made a total mess when I left.
I said all kinds of things
to your grandma and the ladies,
yelling like someone
who would never come back.
How could I go back now?
Oh my goodness.
I'm so mad that this is all I amounted to.
Let's eat something.
Hey, Tae-ha.
Does your wife use cement
instead of makeup or something?
It's just that she has such thick skin.
Why are you so silent?
Right. I guess you can't talk to us ladies
who are so far beneath you.
She just--
Come on, you're just as bad.
Think hard about which side to take,
you spineless dummy.
Do you even know
what she did to your grandmother?
If you still have that mouth of yours
that spewed out all those nasty words,
why don't you say something?
After ruining an 80-year-old woman's
birthday party,
how could you have the nerve
to crawl back here?
I told her to come.
You did, ma'am?
Yes, I asked her to come back.
Hey, Song-wol.
She's not in her right mind
right now, is she?
What if I'm not?
Are you going to kick her out?
Of course we wouldn't…
I just asked my family to return.
Do you have a problem with that?
So leave the girl alone now.
Okay?
By any chance,
did you ask your grandma to do that?
How would I know
when she'd come to her senses?
Then why…
Because she's my grandma.
I have to go to the gym real quick.
Okay.
I have to… go somewhere too.
We're not just stretching and twisting
this taffy for no reason.
We're letting air into it.
If you keep flattening and folding
the taffy over and over,
it forms air bubbles in the center.
The air bubbles
make it sweeter and crumblier.
That's how we make better taffy.
It's the same for people.
Not having any flaws
isn't always a good thing.
If you end up having a few holes
for whatever reason,
you'll find that your tough life
becomes sweeter and crumblier.
And it'll make you a better person.
So it's okay to be a little embarrassed.
It's completely fine for a person
to be embarrassed once in a while.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I thought you were a lady,
but you're just a baby.
Look at you.
Hello.
Tae-ha, that punk…
He was no ordinary kid.
In just six months of training with me,
he swept the city, province,
and national competitions.
In no time, he became a national athlete
and trained at Taereung.
But then, the old lady became unwell.
His grandmother?
Yes. Though she's technically
not his real grandmother.
She's not his real grandmother?
With nowhere to go, Tae-ha's mom
stumbled into our village with a newborn,
then died after staying at
Lady Go's house for a while.
So the old lady raised Tae-ha.
I thought they were family.
They are family.
Do they have to be blood-related
to be family?
That's it! My Tae-ha, you're doing great.
Tae-ha, don't get worked up.
Stop!
She raised him with more care
than she would her own grandchildren.
-Wasn't I great?
-Yes!
The old lady was so warm,
showering him with endless love.
My baby, you did great.
Until then, there were no shadows
in Tae-ha's life.
TAE-HA, GRANDMA COLLAPSED
COME TO BODEUM HOSPITAL CANCER CENTER
Perhaps that's why
he wanted to save her no matter what.
But the surgery and medication
cost nearly a hundred million,
and Tae-ha was only 20 years old.
Where could he get that kind of money?
He couldn't afford it
with his training camp allowance,
and his signing bonus
from the semipro team wasn't much.
And that's when
this gang called Geukrakpa
reached out to him.
His grandma survived,
but when she found out
how Tae-ha had saved her,
she soon started to slip away.
She couldn't go on living
without erasing the memory of that.
After Tae-ha became a gangster,
he lived like a machine.
Beating people up
and breaking things on command.
He lived like that for 14 years,
afraid that he might have regrets
if he ever looked back.
But he's always been too kind by nature.
No matter how much
he tried to live like a machine,
he couldn't help
but feel sick to his stomach.
That's why
he came back.
Tae-ha's heart
is deeply wounded.
A wound that will never heal
and that will never fade.
I don't know about anyone else,
but you…
I just hope you won't make
that wound any worse.
-Excuse me.
-Sure.
Hello.
Yes, this is Hong's Boxing Gym.
Sorry?
Tae-ha?
You're honestly blaming me for this?
I told you that bastard
broke my side mirror and just ran off!
Come on now.
He said he had an emergency
and left his contact information.
Did he not?
Then why didn't he call me
after he was done?
I had to call him and drag him out here!
How is this not a hit-and-run?
You didn't have to mess up his face.
Violence can never be justified!
-What the hell happened?
-There you are.
Go Eun-sae.
Did you get beat up?
No, I…
Oh, dear God.
-Where is your family burial ground?
-What now?
Bow in that direction. Now.
If he's held back any less,
you'd be joining your ancestors by now.
What the hell are you on about?
I'm his guardian.
I'll replace that side mirror
with the fanciest one out there.
Talk it out with me.
You're laughing? You think this is funny?
-You wanna go?
-Let's go talk.
Do-yeop, you can't hit him.
I thought you were a good boxer.
A former gangster.
Couldn't you have just knocked him out
with a few punches?
It wouldn't have taken a few.
Just one.
Exactly.
So why did you let him
beat you up like this?
I didn't get beat up.
I was blocking, and…
I promised you.
What?
I won't ever use my fists
outside the ring anymore.
I promise.
That's why…
you just let him beat you up?
Mr. Jang Tae-ha.
Are you stupid?
Why would you stand there and take it
when you did nothing wrong?
You hit back in situations like this.
You should have hit him back.
What should I do with you?
This must be why I liked you.
Gangster or not,
that must be why.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for not remembering you
and making you upset.
OUR STICKY LOVE
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi